A Guide to the Inge family papers, 1938-2008
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Inge family papers, 1938-2008
The Library of Virginia
45566
1.35 cu. ft. and 3 boxes.
Inge family.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Diann Byrd Inge of Farmville.
Biographical Information
Richard Dabney Inge was born 21 March 1916 in Appomattox County, Virginia, to Dabney Richard Inge (1877-1938) and Mildred Beford Paulette Inge (1883-1970). He attended school in Appomattox County, graduating from high school. Inge attended the Coyne Electrical School in Chicago, Illinois, in 1940 and became an electrician in Farmville, Virginia. He enlisted in the United States Army 3 February 1941, and served in Company G, 116th Infantry Division during World War II. He landed in Normandy, France, 30 minutes after H-Hour on D-Day. After the war ended, Inge returned to Farmville and worked as an electrician and in the Postal Service. He married Rosa Elizabeth Martin (1920-2010) 9 June 1942, and they had two daughters. Inge died in Farmville 14 April 2009, and was buried in the Rocks Baptist Church Cemetery in Appomattox County.
Rosa Elizabeth Martin was born 21 February 1920, in Appomattox County, Virginia, to Lacy Blassingame Martin (1886-1944) and Anna Bernice Cawthorn Martin (1889-1976). She attended Radford College for two years, and received a bachelor of science and a master of arts from Longwood College. Rosa Inge taught school in Amherst, Appomattox, Cumberland, and Prince Edward Counties, Virginia, and at Prince Edward Academy. She married Richard Dabney Inge (1916-2009) on 9 June 1942, and they had two daughters. Rosa Inge died in Prince Edward County on 25 May 2010 and is buried in the Rocks Baptist Church Cemetery in Appomattox County.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1938-2008, of the Inge family consisting of letters, clippings, contracts, envelopes, genealogies, greeting cards, invitations, photographs, postcards, receipts, and telegrams detailing the courtship and marriage of Richard Dabney Inge (1916-2009) and Rosa Elizabeth Martin Inge (1920-2010) of Appomattox County, Farmville, and Lynchburg, Virginia. Papers also discuss Richard's training as an electrician and his service in the United States army during World War II and Rosa's education and her career as a teacher.
Contents List
- Letters, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters, January 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters, February 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters, March 1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters, April 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters, May 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters, June-July 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters, August 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters, September 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters, October 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters, November 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters, December 1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Letters, January 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Letters, February 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Letters, March 1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Letters, April 1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Letters, May 1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Letters, June 1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Letters, July-December 1940 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Letters, January 1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Letters, February 1941 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Letters, March 1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters, April 1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Letters, May 1941 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Letters, June 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letters, July-October 1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Letters, November 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Letters, December 1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Letters, January 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Letters, February 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Letters, 2-17 March 1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Letters, 18-29 March 1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Letters, 3-19 April 1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Letters, 20-29 April 1942 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Letters, 2-19 May 1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Letters, 20-30 May 1942 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Letters, 1-5 June 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Letters, 15-19 June 1942 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Letters, 21-30 June 1942 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Letters, 1-10 July 1942 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Letters, 11-24 July 1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Letters, August-September 1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Letters, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Letters, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Letters, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Letters, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Letters, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Letters, 1964, 1994, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Envelopes, 1939-1946, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Photographs (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Photographs and clippings (with CD) (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Inge family genealogy (also on CD) (Box 3, Folder 17)